Mss.B.B445
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Murray, Thomas F., Jr, 1938 July - 1939 June (Box 14, Folder 36)
    Letters to Max Bergmann inviting him to address the Rochester Section of the American Chemical Society.
  - N - Misc., No. 1, 1937 October - 1943 May (Box 14, Folder 37)
    N - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting positions in Max Bergmann's lab, invitations, requests for reprints, and letters discussing experiments.
  - N - Misc., No. 2, 1934 July - 1942 September (Box 14, Folder 38)
    N - Misc., No. 2
  - N - Misc., No. 3, 1934 March - 1942 September (Box 15, Folder 1)
    N - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters discussing experiments. Requests for samples. Notes of thanks. Letters of recommendation.
  - Nagy, Stephen M., 1940 July - 1945 December (Box 15, Folder 2)
    Nagy, Stephen M.
    Letters from Max Bergmann to Nagy discussing his recovery. A letter of recommendation for Nagy.
  - National Geographic Society, 1942 November - 1943 October (Box 15, Folder 3)
    National Geographic Society
    Letters concerning membership fees and nominations. A pamphlet detailing the benefits of membership.
  - National Research Council, No. 1, 1939 January (Box 15, Folder 4)
    National Research Council, No. 1
    Notice of a National Research Council scholarship for Robert A. Harte. A copy of an application for a National Research Council scholarship.
  - National Research Council, No. 2, 1946 November (Box 15, Folder 5)
    National Research Council, No. 2
    A report from the "Committee on Growth of the Divivsion of Medical Sciences," given on November 6, 1946.
  - National Research Council, No. 3, 1939 April (Box 15, Folder 6)
    National Research Council, No. 3
    Minutes of meetings, April 1, 1939.
  - National Research Council, No. 4, 1940 April (Box 15, Folder 7)
    National Research Council, No. 4
    Minutes of meetings, April 7, 1940.
  - National Research Council, No. 5, 1938 June (Box 15, Folder 8)
    National Research Council, No. 5
    Reports for committes 1937-38. Roster for 1938-39.
  - Nelson, J. M., 1939 October - 1942 September (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Nelson, J. M.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Nelson. Bergmann invites Nelson to meetings at the Rockefeller Institute. Nelson invites Bergmann to Columbia. Bergmann writes to Nelson requesting information about a Dr. Saul Soloway.
  - Neuberg, Carl, 1934 April - July (Box 15, Folder 10)
    Neuberg, Carl
    Letters concerning employment for Neuberg.
  - Neumann, F. S., 1940 July - September (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Neurath, Hans, 1935 May - 1943 September (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Neurath, Hans
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Hans Neurath. Requests for chemical samples and reprints from Max Bergmann. Neurath asks Bergmann for advice on a manuscript.
  - New York Academy of Sciences, No. 1, 1942 April - 1944 November (Box 15, Folder 13)
    New York Academy of Sciences, No. 1
    Notices of papers and reprints, tickets to conferences, a series of printed abstracts from a conference in February, 1944.
  - New York Academy of Sciences, No. 2, 1941 December - 1943 February (Box 15, Folder 14)
    New York Academy of Sciences, No. 2
    Notice of Max Bergmann becoming a Fellow of the New York Academy of Sciences. Max Bergmann writes letters to the Academy on behalf of Stanford Moore, Mark Stahmann, and Calvin Golumbic.
  - Niemann, Carl George, No. 1, 1942 February - 1944 November (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Niemann, Carl George, No. 1
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Carl Niemann. Bergmann writes Niemann seeking someone to work in his lab. Bergmann writes a letter recommending Niemann to the National Defense Board 1943. A letter of support for Niemann being awarded the American Chemical Society Award in Pure Chemistry. A notice of Bergmann's death.
  - Niemann, Carl George, No. 2, 1937 December - 1940 May (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Niemann, Carl George, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Carl Niemann. Both professional and personal letters. Letter to Niermann about publishing joint papers on collagen-gelatin. Bergmann discusses his depression regarding his German contemporaries.
  - Nord, F. F., No. 1, 1935 December - 1940 December (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Nord, F. F.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Nord.
  - Nord, F. F., No. 2, 1941 January - 1942 January (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Nord, F. F., No. 2
  - Norris, Earl R., 1939 October - 1940 September (Box 15, Folder 19)
    Norris, Earl R.
    Letters requesting samples of salmon pepsin.
  - Northrop, John Howard, No. 1, 1941 March - 1942 March (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Northrop, John Howard, No. 1
    Letters discussing a paper written by Max Bergmann for publication in the "Journal of General Physiology."
  - Northrop, John Howard, No. 2, 1934 March - 1940 March (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Northrop, John Howard, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Northrop. Letters regarding experiements. Requests for reprints.
  - Norton, Margaret I., 1938 May - 1940 January (Box 15, Folder 22)
    Norton, Margaret I.
    Recommended to Max Bergmann by Dr. Albert R. Frank. Norton writes Bergmann about employment in the United States.
  - Noyes, William Albert, 1938 December - 1939 November (Box 15, Folder 23)
    Noyes, William Albert
    Noyes sends details to Max Bergmann regarding Dr. Else Hirschberg who needs help leaving Germany. Curriculum vitae included.
  - O - Misc., 1938 April - 1941 December (Box 15, Folder 24)
    O - Misc.
  - O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 1, 1935 January - 1937 March (Box 15, Folder 25)
    O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 1
    General correspondence bewteen Max Bergmann and O'Flaherty. Letters discussing the work of both Bergmann and O'Flaherty. Requests for reprints. A letter informing Max Bergmann of his becoming a member of the American Leather Chemists Association.
  - O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 2, 1941 January - 1944 April (Box 15, Folder 26)
    O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and O'Flaherty. Letters concerning Bergmann's attendance at the annual meeting of the American Leather Chemists Association.
  - O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 3, 1934 May - 1935 February (Box 15, Folder 27)
    O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 3
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and O'Flaherty. Letters discussing experiements. Requests for samples.
  - O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 4, 1937 March - 1940 September (Box 15, Folder 28)
    O'Flaherty, Fred, No. 4
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and O'Flaherty. Requests for reprints. Invitations for Bergmann to present lectures. Letters discussing experiments.
  - Oppenheimer, Benjamin S., 1939 April - 1944 June (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Oppenheimer, Benjamin S.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Benjamin Oppenheimer. Abstracts for papers. Letters discussing experiments. Requests and notes of thanks for reprints. A letter from Oppenheimer requesting that Bergmann give the Janeway Lecture in 1939.
  - Oppenheimer, Carl, 1937 October - 1940 December (Box 16, Folder 2)
    Oppenheimer, Carl
    Letters regarding an article to be written by Max Bergmann for the journal "Enzymologia."
  - Oppenheim-Errera, Stephane, 1942 March (Box 16, Folder 3)
    Oppenheim-Errera, Stephane
    Letters discuss employment in Bergman's lab. Includes curriculum vitae for Oppenheim-Errera.
  - Oriental Science Literature Service, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    Oriental Science Literature Service
    Circulars.
  - Osterhout, W. J. V., 1934 November - 1942 April (Box 16, Folder 5)
    Osterhout, W. J. V.
    Requests and notes of thanks for reprints.
  - P - Misc., No. 1, 1935 April - 1944 October (Box 16, Folder 6)
    P - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters of recommendation. Invitations. Requests for reprints. Requests for chemical samples.
  - P - Misc., No. 2, 1935 April - 1944 October (Box 16, Folder 7)
    P - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous material. Includes letters of recommendation, requests for reprints, requests for chemical samples, and letters discussing experimental procedures.
  - P - Misc., No. 3, 1937 January - 1943 September (Box 16, Folder 8)
    P - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous material. Requests for reprints. Invitations. Letters discussing experiments. Subscription renewals.
  - P - Misc., No. 4, 1936 January - 1937 December (Box 16, Folder 9)
    P - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous material. Includes a copy of "Science Services" which discusses Max Bergmann's work.
  - Palmer, Albert H., 1937 September - 1939 September (Box 16, Folder 10)
    Palmer, Albert H.
    Letters requesting reprints and chemical samples from Max Bergmann.
  - Papain, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Papaya, undated (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Papers, undated (Box 16, Folder 13)
    Papers
    Six photographs of complex compounds and two papers titled, "The Quantitative Determination of Amino Acids," and "The Mode of Action of Proteinases."
  - Parker, J. Gordon, 1934 April - 1939 November (Box 16, Folder 14)
    Parker, J. Gordon
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and L. Gordon Parkman.
  - Pauling, Linus, 1941 April - 1943 October (Box 16, Folder 15)
    Pauling, Linus
    Letters concerning the nomination of Dr. Carl Niemann for the American Chemical Society award in Pure Chemistry. Requests for reprints.
  - Pearce, Agnes M., 1939 August - 1940 September (Box 16, Folder 16)
    Pearce, Agnes M.
    Letters concerning the position of Dr. Chi-yuan Chou in Bergmann's lab.
  - Peptides, undated (Box 16, Folder 17)
    Peptides
  - Peroff, S., 1935 April (Box 16, Folder 18)
    Peroff, S.
    A letter from Max Bergman recommending Alexander Kiesel to Peroff. Includes a list of Kiesel's publications.
  - Personal, 1936 July - 1941 March (Box 16, Folder 19)
    Personal
    Miscellaneous pesonal materials. Correspondence between Max Bergmann and his secretary, Miss von Berg, while he is on vacation.
  - Perutz, Max, 1943 November (Box 16, Folder 20)
    Perutz, Max
    Letters arranging a meeting with Max Bergmann in New York.
  - Peterson, W., 1942 August - 1943 March (Box 16, Folder 21)
    Peterson, W.
    Letters of introduction and letters of recommendation.
  - Petter, Charles K., 1944 February - March (Box 16, Folder 22)
    Petter, Charles K.
    Letters concerning an article written by Petter.
  - Phillips, Catherine, 1944 June - October (Box 16, Folder 23)
    Phillips, Catherine
    Max Bergmann writes letters of recommendation for Catherine Phillips.
  - Pigman, W. W., 1943 October - 1944 April (Box 16, Folder 24)
    Pigman, W. W.
    Letters concerning Max Bergmann's contribution to the journal "Advances in Carbohydrate Chemistry."
  - Plentl, Albert A., 1943 March - 1944 April (Box 16, Folder 25)
    Plentl, Albert A.
    Letters discussing Max Bergmann's reviews and comments on Plentl's manuscripts. Includes copies of two corrected manuscripts titled,"On the Enzymatic Specificity of Renin I," and "The Proteinase Components of Renin-Preparations and Their Relation to Renin Activity." Also requests for both reprints and chemical samples.
  - Pollak, Fritz, 1938 November (Box 16, Folder 26)
    Pollak, Fritz
    A letter from Max Bergmann to Fritz Pollack on behalf of a Dr. Walter who is seeking employment.
  - Pollak, Leopold, 1934 June - 1941 September (Box 16, Folder 27)
    Pollak, Leopold
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Leopold Pollak.
  - Pollok, Heinz, 1937 October - 1939 February (Box 16, Folder 28)
    Scope and Contents note
  - Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn, 1942 January (Box 16, Folder 29)
    Polytechnic Institute of Brooklyn
    Invitations to speeches, lectures, and symposium.
  - Ponder, Eric, 1938 April - June (Box 16, Folder 30)
    Ponder, Eric
    Arrangements for a symposium in June, 1938.
  - Pons, Henry W., 1943 March - April (Box 16, Folder 31)
    Pons, Henry W.
    Correspondence between Max Bergmann and Henry Pons (formerly Heinz Pollock). Pons, attempting to become a United States citizen, writes to Bergmann for a letter of recommendation.
  - Porter, J. R., 1940 January (Box 16, Folder 32)
    Porter, J. R.
    Letters discussing the location of various chemicals.
  - Positions, 1941 September (Box 16, Folder 33)
    Positions
    Notices from the United States Civil Service for several available positions.
  - Potter, Robert D., 1937 December (Box 16, Folder 34)
    Potter, Robert D.
    Letters concerning a presentation to be given by Max Bergmann at the Organic Chemistry Symposium in Richmond, Virginia.
  - Preparations, undated (Box 16, Folder 35)
    Preparations
  - Prochownick, Vilma, 1934 April - 1936 February (Box 16, Folder 36)
    Prochownick, Vilma
    Letters concerning employment oppurtunities in the United States. Curriculum vitae included.
  - Proskauer, Erich, 1938 November - 1941 August (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Proskauer, Erich
    Letters concerning upcoming publications.
  - Protein Committee, 1938 March - 1940 November (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Protein Committee
    Notice of meetings and agendas of activities. Letter from Charles L. Parsons of the American Chemical Society to Levene. Minutes of meeting from 19398-1940. Lists of members 1939-40 and 1940-41.
  - Proteins, 1941 March - June (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Proteins
    Notices of different protein conferences.
  - Q - Misc., 1940 October - 1942 May (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Q - Misc.
    General miscellaneous material. Curriculum vitae for a Dr. Juda Hirsch Quastel. A letter soliciting donations the "Queen Wilhelmina Fund."
  - R - Misc., No. 1, 1939 September - 1943 March (Box 17, Folder 5)
    R - Misc., No. 1
    General miscellaneous materials. Requests for reprints. Letters of recommendation. Requests for chemical samples.
  - R - Misc., No. 2, 1939 February - 1943 July (Box 17, Folder 6)
    R - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous material. Letters of reference. A letter from the National Refugee Service to Max Bergmann requesting his appearence in a film being made by the Office of War Information. Letters from various refugee scientists seeking Bergmann's help in finding employment.
  - R - Misc., No. 3, 1934 June - 1940 April (Box 17, Folder 7)
    R - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous material. Receipts of payments. Notes of thanks. Requests for reprints.
  - R - Misc., No. 4, 1934 June - 1943 October (Box 17, Folder 8)
    R - Misc., No. 4
    General miscellaneous material. Notes of thanks. Letters of introduction. Requests for reprints.
  - Rabinowitsch, E., 1938 February - June (Box 17, Folder 9)
    Rabinowitsch, E.
    Curriculum vitae and list of publications to 1937 for Rabinowitsch. Letters of reference. Max Bergmann recommends him to the Bureau of Employment of the Chemists Club of New York.
  - Raistrick, H., 1934 October - 1939 December (Box 17, Folder 10)
    Raistrick, H.
    Exchange of reprints.
  - Rapport, Maurice M., 1941 November (Box 17, Folder 11)
    Rapport, Maurice M.
    A letter of recommendation for Maurice Rapport written by Max Bergmann.
  - Receipts, 1946 March - May (Box 17, Folder 12)
    Receipts
    Miscellaneous receipts of purchase from the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Refugee Correspondence, 1942 May - 1944 September (Box 17, Folder 13)
    Refugee Correspondence
    Miscellaneous materials concerning refugee scientists.
  - Reich, Hans, 1934 October - 1935 October (Box 17, Folder 14)
    Reich, Hans
    Correspondence concerning employment in the United States for Hans Reich.
  - Reichstein, T., 1940 October - 1941 April (Box 17, Folder 15)
    Reichstein, T.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Reichstein. Requests for chemical samples and reprints. Letters discussing a job for Hermann Fischer, a German refugee scientist.
  - Reimann, Guenter, 1941 April (Box 17, Folder 16)
    Reimann, Guenter
    Letters concerning the situation of a Dr. Scwarzkoff. Reimann writes to Max Bergmann informing him that Scwarzkoff was stuck in France waiting for the U.S. State Department to grant him a visa. Bergmann writes a letter on Scwarzkoff's behalf.
  - Reis, Alfred J., 1942 January - April (Box 17, Folder 17)
    Reis, Alfred J.
    Letters discussing the prospects of employment for Reis. Curriculum vitae and publications list included. Reis writes to Max Bergmann to see if he can be of assistance to Dr. Moritz Cohn.
  - Remington, Roe E., 1934 June - July (Box 17, Folder 18)
    Remington, Roe E.
    Letters discussing a speaking engagement to be attended by Max Bergmann.
  - Report of the Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    Report of the Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature
    A report prepared for the Committee on Carbohydrate Nomenclature of the American Chemical Society.
  - Reprint Requests, 1939 February - 1940 June (Box 17, Folder 20)
    Reprint Requests
  - Reprint List, undated (Box 17, Folder 21)
    Reprint List
    A list of Max Bergmann's publications, 1918-1941.
  - Resinous Products and Chemical Corporation, 1944 June (Box 17, Folder 22)
    Resinous Products and Chemical Corporation
    Letters discussing an experiment. An order for chemicals.
  - Reviews, 1942 September - 1945 October (Box 17, Folder 23)
    Reviews
    Letters concerning reviews written by Max Bergmann. A copy of a published review in the journal "Science."
  - Rewald, Bruno, 1938 November - 1941 July (Box 17, Folder 24)
    Rewald, Bruno
    Requests for reprints. Letter from Rewald to Bergmann seeking help in gaining entry to the United States.
  - Rewald, Walter, 1939 April - 1941 September (Box 17, Folder 25)
    Rewald, Walter
    A letter concerning the position of Rewald's father, Walter Rewald, who is trying to gain entrance to the United States.
  - Rideal, Eric K., 1936 March - May (Box 17, Folder 26)
    Rideal, Eric K.
    Letter to Max Bergmann requesting tannin derivatives. Requests for reprints.
  - Robbins, William J., 1942 January (Box 17, Folder 27)
    Robbins, William J.
    Letters requesting chemicals and reprints from Max Bergmann.
  - Robertson, Albert D., 1935 October - 1940 October (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Robertson, Albert D.
    Letters concerning tax forms.
  - Roche e Silva, 1941 June - 1943 May (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Roche e Silva
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Roche e Silva. Letter from Roche e Silva informing Bergmann that he has been awarded a Guugenheim Fellowship and will be working in Bergmann's lab. Letters requesting Bergmann's advice on several of his publication drafts.
  - The Rockefeller Foundation, 1944 October (Box 18, Folder 3)
    The Rockefeller Foundation
    Letter requesting information regarding Sidney W. Fox.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.1, 1934 April - 1940 April (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.1
    General miscellaneous materials regarding the Rockefeller Institute. Max Bergmann's job acceptance note, April 24, 1934. Invitations to lunch and dinner. A list of appointments and promotions 1936, 1939-40.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.2, 1940 - 1945 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.2
    Budgets for Max Bergmann's lab at the Rockefeller Institute, 1940 - 1945.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.3, 1941 Janaury - 1943 May (Box 18, Folder 6)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.3
    Annual lists of publications available from the Rockefeller Instititute form May 1941 - May 1943.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.4, 1941 September - 1941 October (Box 18, Folder 7)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.4
    Letters concerning the Program Committee of the Committee of the Staff Meetings at the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.5, 1938 July (Box 18, Folder 8)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.5
    Receipts for money spent in Max Bergmann's lab for the year 1938.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.6, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    Rockefeller Institute, No.6
    A 1945 report from Max Bergmann's lab prepared by Joseph Fruton.
  - Rockefeller Institute, No.6, 1938 January - 1942 May (Box 18, Folder 10)
    Notes concerning staff meetings at the Rockefeller Institute.
  - Rohm & Haas, 1941 September - 1942 August (Box 18, Folder 11)
    Rohm & Haas
    Letters requesting chemical samples. Letters to Max Bergmann requesting information about chemists available to work in their lab.
  - Rosin, Jacob, 1940 December (Box 18, Folder 12)
    Rosin, Jacob
    Letters discussing employment for Rosin. Includes curriculum vitae and a letter of reference.
  - Ross, William F., No.1, 1936 October - 1939 November (Box 18, Folder 13)
    Ross, William Fenton, No.1
    General correspondence concerning Max Bergmann's help in getting Ross a job at Harvard. Plans for visiting each other. Exchange of reprints.
  - Ross, William F., No.2, 1941 November - 1943 March (Box 18, Folder 14)
    Ross, William Fenton, No.2
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Ross.
  - Rous, Peyton, 1941 December - 1943 February (Box 18, Folder 15)
    Rous, Peyton
    Letters concerning reviews of several publications.
  - Rugo, Henry J., 1940 September - 1941 May (Box 18, Folder 16)
    Rugo, Henry J.
    Letters from Rugo requesting a visit to Max Bergmann's lab. Requests for chemical samples.
  - Ruzicka, L., 1937 September - 1940 February (Box 18, Folder 17)
    Ruzicka, L.
    General correspondence between Max Bergmann and Ruzicka. Ruzicka writes letters of recommendation for a Dr. Hoffmann and Max Brenner to work in Bergmann's lab. Bergmann writes to Ruzika congratulating him on winning the Nobel Prize in 1939.
  - S - Misc., No. 1, 1934 May - 1943 December (Box 18, Folder 18)
    S - Misc., No. 1
  - S - Misc., No. 2, 1934 April - 1946 May (Box 18, Folder 19)
    S - Misc., No. 2
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters requesting positions in Max Bergmann's lab. Christmas cards. Requests for reprints. A notification of Bergmann's death.
  - S - Misc., No. 3, 1934 October - 1945 December (Box 18, Folder 20)
    S - Misc., No. 3
    General miscellaneous materials. Requests for reprints. Letters of recommendation. A bound copy of the curriculum vitae for Dr. Paul Wessel. Magazine subscriptions.
  - S - Misc., No. 4, 1935 January - 1942 August (Box 18, Folder 21)
    S - Misc., No. 4
  - S - Misc., No. 5, 1934 May - 1941 June (Box 18, Folder 22)
    S - Misc., No. 5
    General miscellaneous materials. Plans for road trips. Notes of thanks. Letter requesting money for the safe passage of a German refugee.
  - S - Misc., No. 6, 1934 June - 1942 July (Box 18, Folder 23)
    S - Misc., No. 6
    General miscellaneous materials. Requests for chemical samples and reprints. Letters of recommendation. Letters dsicussing experiments.
  - S - Misc., No. 7, 1936 April - 1940 November (Box 18, Folder 24)
    S - Misc., No. 7
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters of recommendation. Curriculum vitae for Frances and Hugo Stern. Requests for reprints. Invitations to speaking engagements.
  - S - Misc., No. 8, 1941 November - 1945 March (Box 18, Folder 25)
    S - Misc., No. 8
    General miscellaneous materials. Requests for reprints. Notes of thanks. Notice of Max Bergmann's death.
  - S - Misc., No. 9, 1934 June - 1944 September (Box 18, Folder 26)
    S - Misc., No. 9
    General miscellaneous materials. Letters of introduction. Notes of thanks. Requests for reprints.
  - Sabine, David, 1938 May - 1945 February (Box 19, Folder 1)
    Sabine, David
    Requests for reprints. Sabine writes to Max Bergmann for advice on experiments.
  - Sack, Anne, 1942 May - October (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Sack, Anne
    Letters concerning employment for Sack. A letter introducing Sack to Max Bergmann. Bergmann writes to several colleagues on behalf of Sack.
  - Salmon, M. R., 1939 February - 1940 February (Box 19, Folder 3)
    Salmon, M. R.